# **Hadi Gunawan**

hadigunawan987@gmail.com | +6285781722743 | South Tangerang, Banten 15424 | linkedin.com/in/hadi-gunawan-875889199/ | Portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

Hello, my name is Hadi Gunawan and I am a fresh graduate from the University of Pamulang majoring in Informatics Engineering, I have work experience for approximately 2 years. I'm Tech-savvy, I have an enthusiasm to work in the data science fields for instance: Jr/Entry level Data Analyst, Business Analyst, etc, but do not rule out opportunities in other fields. Eager to learn and adapt to a new team and company.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Retention and Winback, Myrepublic ID

Aug 2018 - July 2020

- Make outbound calls to customers who have a tendency to churn/move to other competitors in order to minimize the occurrence of churn (customer and target-oriented)
- Keeping touch with customers by escalating reports related to customer problems and rewards to customers. Using **google sheets**, **CRM** and tools for instance: Zendesk, internal CRM, Hermes
- Successfully achieve 100% of KPI every month or even more.

## Data Entry (Vocational School Internship), BP2T South Tangerang

Jan 2016 - Feb 2016

- Entry data into Microsoft Excel, organize physical data into the warehouse, and maintaining them
- Overall got a grade A result.

### LICENSE AND CERTIFICATIONS

### SQL Fundamentals Track (DataCamp)

Learning and practicing about Structured Query Language (SQL), in this course I learning from basic to intermediate, window function, correlated queries, nested queries, Common Table Expressions (CTE), built-in PostgreSQL functions and many more

## Python Fundamentals Track (DataCamp)

Learning and practicing about python from basic (data analysis), learn some packages such as NumPy, matplotlib (Data Visualization), exploratory data analysis (EDA) and Pandas

### Tableau Fundamentals Track (DataCamp)

Learning and practicing about data preparation, data interpretation, identification, data visualization, getting insight from data, building dashboard, make a story of data using tableau.

### And many more..

### **SKILLS**

**Hard Skills and Tools:** Visual Studio Code, Exploratory Data Analysis, Data Interpretation, Data Visualization, Build Dashboard Excel, Word, PowerPoint, SQL, Tableau, Power Bi, Google Sheets, Google Data Studio, HTML, CSS, Github, MySQL, Adobe Photoshop, (Novice: SQL Server, PHP, Python, Flutter, AWS) **Soft Skills:** Communication, Critical Thinking, Teamwork, Adaptability, Problem-Solving, Collaboration.

## **EDUCATION**

	Pamulang University	Sept 2017 – Aug 2021
Bachelor of	•	GPA:
Informatics		3.46/4.00
Engineering		3.40/4.00

**Relevant coursework:** Database, Algorithms and Programming, Data Communication, Statistics, Informatics Logic, Calculus, Basic Physics, Computer Programming, Data Structures, AI, DSS.